Stafford, Ronald B.; Papers apap217
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Photographs, 1981-2002; Undated; 12; 1.60 cubic ft.
  - Stafford with Saranac Lake High School Students at the New York State "LifeSmarts" Competition Finds, 2002 (Box 2 (12-Photographs), Folder 15)
  - Stafford with Senator Bruno, 2002 (Box 2 (12-Photographs), Folder 16)
  - Stafford with SUNY Plattsburgh People, 1995; 1996; 1998 (Box 2 (12-Photographs), Folder 17)
  - Stafford with Thomas and Catherine Somich, 2002 (Box 2 (12-Photographs), Folder 18)
  - Stafford with Unidentified People, 1995-2000; Undated (Box 2 (12-Photographs), Folder 19-20)
  - Unidentified Students, 1995 (Box 2 (12-Photographs), Folder 21)
  - Various Poses, Fall, 1994 (Box 3 (12-Photographs), Folder 1)
  - Veterans, 1992; 1997-1998; 2000 (Box 3 (12-Photographs), Folder 2)
  - Ward Lumbar Mill Tour, 1992 (Box 3 (12-Photographs), Folder 3)
  - West Point Cadets, 2001 (Box 3 (12-Photographs), Folder 4)
  - Women of Distinction, 1998-2001 (Box 3 (12-Photographs), Folder 5)
  - World Trade Center Site, 2001 (Box 3 (12-Photographs), Folder 6)
  - 4-H Groups, 1996-1999; 2000; Undated (Box 3 (12-Photographs), Folder 7)
- Press Releases, 1970-1988; 13; 1.00 cubic ft.
  This series contains press and photo releases issued by Senator Ronald Stafford's office. The majority of releases date from the years 1978-1981. There are also newsclippings from the 1970s.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1970 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1971 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1976 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 3)
  - New Release, 1978 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 4)
  - Capital Comments, 1978 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 5)
  - Capital Comments, 1979 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 6)
  - News Releases, 1979 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 7)
  - Capital Comments, 1980 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 8)
  - Fee Raise, 1980 January 04 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 9)
  - 3- year Budget, 1980 January 11 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 10)
  - Photo Release: Rouses Point Administrator, 1980 January 25 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 11)
  - Photo Release, VFW, 1980 January 28 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 12)
  - Photo Releases: Sheriff's Association, 1980 January 30 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 13)
  - Tax Plan Passes, 1980 February 20 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 14)
  - Ti- Hospital, 1980 March 07 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 15)
  - R.R. Property Tax, 1980 March 11 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 16)
  - Student Art Show, 1980 March 14 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 17)
  - Washington County Court, 1980 March 14 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 18)
  - Saratogian-Gun Control, 1980 March 19 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 19)
  - Prison Guards, 1980 April 14 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 20)
  - Statement: Gun Control Mrng, 1980 April 16 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 21)
  - Chateagay Bill, 1980 May 07 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 22)
  - Policy Forum, 1980 May 14 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 23)
  - Re-election Announcement, 1980 May 22 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 24)
  - Martin Endorsement, 1980 August 20 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 25)
  - Labarge Endorsement, 1980 August 22 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 26)
  - Magistrates Speech, 1980 September 17 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 27)
  - End of Fuel Tax, 1980 October 02 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 28)
  - O'Neil Endorsement, 1980 October 09 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 29)
  - Bus Contractors Speech, 1980 October 22 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 30)
  - Stafford Program For 1981, 1980 October 24 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 31)
  - Substantial State Aid Increases for Libraries, 1981 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 32)
  - Stafford News Clippings, 1981 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 33)
  - Capitol Comments, 1981 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 34)
  - Comments on Criminal Justice Plan, 1981 January 07 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 35)
  - "Fiscal System Outdate" (3 Year Budget), 1981 January 14 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 36)
  - VFW Photo Release 1980, 1981 January 22 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 37)
  - Snow-Ice Removal (Town Costs), 1981 January 28 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 38)
  - Photo Releases-Local Sheriffs Meet with Legislators, 1981 February 03 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 39)
  - (Press Repub. Article) Dead Wood Bill, 1981 February 04 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 40)
  - Aid for Flood Victims, 1981 March 05 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 41)
  - Photo Release-4-H Delegates, 1981 March 16 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 42)
  - Photo Release-Franklin, Essex, & Washington Countries Farm Bureau, 1981 April 02 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 43)
  - Ticonderoga Central-4th and 5th Graders, 1981 April 03 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 44)
  - Stafford's Offchore Agricultural Labor Bill Passes Senate, 1981 May 28 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 45)
  - Senate Passes Deep Bill, 1981 June 03 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 46)
  - Photo Releases-Senator Stafford Meets with Reverend Butler's Family, 1981 June 17 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 47)
  - Stafford's Plattsburgh State Campus School Bill Passes Senate and Assembly, 1981 July 03 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 48)
  - Senator Stafford Hosts Senate Exhibit at Fair, 1981 July 22 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 49)
  - Stafford Opposed to Reallocating Hydroelectric Power, 1981 July 23 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 50)
  - Stafford Opposed to Renaming of St. Lawrence Power Project, 1981 August 21 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 51)
  - Capitol Comments, 1982 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 52)
  - VFW Photo Release-Washington and Warren Co., 1982 February 01 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 53)
  - Photo Release: Senator Stafford Meets with Students and Faculty from Chateaugay Central, 1982 February 05 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 54)
  - Opening of Washington County Office, 1982 March 11 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 55)
  - 4-H Delegates Meet with Senator Stafford, 1982 March 15 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 56)
  - Clinton, Franklin, and Washington County Farm Bureau with Senator, 1982 March 24 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 57)
  - Senator Meets with All State Band Member, 1982 March 24 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 58)
  - Funds Secured for Adirondacker Train (Amtrak), 1982 March 25 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 59)
  - Stafford Meets with Life Underwriters from Plattsburgh and Brasher Falls, 1982 March 30 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 60)
  - Farm Bureau Youth-Franklin and St. Lawrence Co., 1982 March 30 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 61)
  - Stafford Meets with Washington County Farm Bureau Youth, 1982 March 30 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 62)
  - Photo Releases: Senator Stafford Meets with State Senate Student Policy Students, 1982 May 24 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 63)
  - Stafford Backs State Aid for Rabies Treatment, 1983 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 64)
  - Governor Cuomo's State of the State, 1983 January 05 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 65)
  - Washington County Veterans Meet with Stafford, 1983 January 24 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 66)
  - Photo Release: Stafford and Ryan Meet with Clinton County Officials, 1983 March 10 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 67)
  - Stafford Calls for State Aid to Countries for Reassessment Expenses, 1983 February 16 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 68)
  - Stafford Backs "Medevac" Unit Forn. Country, 1983 February 23 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 69)
  - Senators Meets with Student Art Show Exhibitors, 1983 March 09 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 70)
  - Photo Release: Stafford Meets with Warren County Officials, 1983 March 10 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 71)
  - Stafford Calls for Funds for Gore Mountain Ski Center, 1983 April 05 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 72)
  - Stafford Meets with Northeastern Clinton Teacher and Student, 1983 May 11 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 73)
  - Stafford Meets with Salem Central Students and Teacher, 1983 May 11 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 74)
  - Photo Release: Stafford Meets with I Love New York Spring Poster Pageant Winners, 1983 June 03 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 75)
  - Stafford Hosts Lake George High School Musical Groups, 1983 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 76)
  - Senator Stafford Announces Passage of Bill That Repeal 3-Year Liquor License, 1983 June 08 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 77)
  - Assembly Bills, 1987-1988 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 78-81)
  - Senate Bills, 1987-1988 (Box 1 (13-Press Releases), Folder 82)
- News Clippings, 1982 January 22-1990 November 25; Undated; 14; 2.40 cubic ft.
  This series contains news clippings typically pertaining to Senator Ronald Stafford and his legislation. Clippings from 1987-1990 as well as some from 1984 were originally kept in binders titled Senator Clips. Others were loose pages kept in a separate box.
  - Senator Clips, 1982 January 22-1982 December 28 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 1)
  - Senator Clips, 1983 January 06-1983 December 22 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 2)
  - Senator Clips, 1984 January 02-1984 March 31 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 3)
  - Senator Clips, 1984 April 01-1984 April 30 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 4)
  - Senator Clips, 1984 May 02-1984 June 30 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 5)
  - Senator Clips, 1984 July 01-1984 October 31 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 6-7)
  - Senator Clips, 1984 November 01-1984 December 27 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 8)
  - Senator Clips, 1985 January 02-1985 March 29 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 9)
  - Senator Clips, 1985 April 01-1985 June 30 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 10)
  - Senator Clips, 1985 July 01-1985 September 30 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 11)
  - Senator Clips, 1985 October 2-1985 November 30 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 12)
  - Senator Clips, 1986 January 01-1986 March 31 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 13)
  - Senator Clips, 1986 April 01-1986 May 29 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 14)
  - Senator Clips, 1986 June 01-1986 August 29 (Box 1 (14-News Clippings), Folder 15)
  - Senator Clips, 1986 November 02-1986 December 31 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 1)
  - Senator Clips, 1987 January 01-1987 March 31 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 2-3)
  - Senator Clips, 1987 April 01-1987 July 31 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 4-5)
  - Senator Clips, 1987 August 01-1987 December 31 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 6-7)
  - Senator Clips, 1988 January 03-1988 March 31 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 8-9)
  - Senator Clips, 1988 April 01-1988 May 31 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 10-11)
  - Senator Clips, 1988 June 01-1988 August 31 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 12-13)
  - Senator Clips, 1988 September 01-1988 October 31 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 14-15)
  - Senator Clips, 1988 November 01-1988 December 31 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 16-17)
  - Senator Clips, 1989 January 12-1989 April 19 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 18)
  - Senator Clips, 1989 March 01-1989 April 28 (Box 2 (14-News Clippings), Folder 19-20)
  - Senator Clips, 1989 May 01-1989 August 31 (Box 3 (14-News Clippings), Folder 21)
  - Senator Clips, 1989 May 01-1989 August 31 (Box 3 (14-News Clippings), Folder 1)
  - Senator Clips, 1989 September 06-1989 December 28 (Box 3 (14-News Clippings), Folder 2-3)
  - Senator Clips, 1990 June 01-1990 July 31 (Box 3 (14-News Clippings), Folder 4-5)
  - Senator Clips, 1990 August 01-1990 November 25 (Box 3 (14-News Clippings), Folder 6)
  - Senator Clips, Undated (Box 3 (14-News Clippings), Folder 7)
- Audiovisual Material, 1967-2002; Undated; 15; 0.80 cubic ft.
  This series contains VHS tapes, audio cassette tapes, and reels of interviews and speeches Senator Ronald Stafford gave while in office.
  - Adirondack: Searching for Common Ground, Undated (Video-tape 1)
  - Adirondack Scenic Railroad, 2001 September (Video-tape 1)
  - Adirondacks, 1991 January 31 (Video-tape 1)
  - Clinton-North American Red Cross Ice Storm '98, Undated (Video-tape 1)
  - Commencement Address, State University at Potsdam, 1970 January 07 (Reel 2)
  - CNN Interview: Senator Joseph L. Bruno, Republican National Convention, 2000 August 02 (Video-tape 1)
  - Day in the Life (with RBS), 1993 February 04-1993 February 05 (Video-tape 1)
  - Donaldson Debate, 1990 (Video-tape 1)
  - For Senator Stafford, Undated (Video-tape 1)
  - Fred Dicker Show, WROW 590AM, 1999 March 31 (Cassette 1)
  - Fred Dicker Show, WROW 590AM, 2001 February 28 (Cassette 2)
  - Fred Dicker Show, WROW 590AM, 2002 January 29 (Cassette 3)
  - Fred Dicker Show, WROW 590AM, 2002 February 06 (Cassette 4)
  - Fred Dicker Show, WROW 590AM, 2002 May 15 (Cassette 5)
  - Fred Dicker Show, WROW 590AM with Betty Little, 2002 February 19 (Cassette 6)
  - Gary Schermerhorn, Undated (Video-tape 1)
  - "Gleaning." PBS WCFE, 1989 November 23 (Video-tape 1)
  - High Peaks Hospice PSA by Senator Stafford, 1998 June 03 (Cassette 7)
  - Inside Albany, 1997 May 10 (Video-tape 1)
  - Inside Albany, 2002 July 08 (Video-tape 1)
  - Inside Albany, on the Adirondacks, 1992 June 20 (Video-tape 1)
  - Lake Champlain Byways, Undated (Video-tape 1)
  - Lawline Visits the New York State Capitol with Senator Ronald B. Stafford, 1992 (Video-tape 1)
  - Leadley's Legacy: An Adirondack Documentary by Mike Camoin, 1996 (Video-tape 1)
  - McKenzie WKBE. Newspiece and Viewpoint, 1992 August (Cassette 8)
  - New York Power Authority Report: Special Edition Ice Storm of 98, 1998 January (Video-tape 2)
  - North County Review: Legislative Issues 1990, 1990 June 01 (Video-tape 2)
  - Plattsburgh Air Force Base: Options for the Future, Undated (Video-tape 2)
  - Priorities: The Adirondack Commission Report, 1990 September 19 (Video-tape 2)
  - Profiles of Power. Profiles of Governor Pataki, Assemblyman Silver and Senator Bruno, Undated (Video-tape 2)
  - Project 67, 1967 January 28 (Reel 3)
  - "Quote Me", 1969 March 16 (Reel 4)
  - RBS on Ken M9Rail Radio Show, 1992 (Cassette 9)
  - RBS with Carol Monroe, 1992 May 27 (Video-tape 2)
  - St. Mary's-St. Alphonsus School, Grade 6 "Recycle Team" Project #31AV-45, Undated (Video-tape 2)
  - Senator Stafford Closing Remarks, 2002 June 02 (Video-tape 2)
  - Senator Stafford PSUC Press Conference, Undated (Video-tape 2)
  - "Speak Up" WWSC, 1992 October 22 (Cassette 10)
  - Stafford, 1978 May 03 (Reel 5)
  - Stafford, WWSC Interview, 1978 April 19 (Reel 6)
  - Stafford, WWSC Interview, 1978 March 17 (Reel 7)
  - Stafford Spots, 1992 (Video-tape 2)
  - Testimonial. "Stafford Testimonial" WPTZ-TV, Undated (Video-tape 2)
  - Unmarked, Undated (Video-tape 2)
  - Unmarked, Undated (Cassette 11)
  - We Oppose Dredging, 2001 May (Video-tape 2)